Self-designed model software simulation
Now software model simulation can be used to self-design virtual models,
including simple non-human shapes or virtual models without bones.
Now add an OBJ or FBX virtual model.
Here we add an OBJ file, then confirm the virtual model that is imported.
Please note that the virtual model you import cannot have a hole or a self-interference problem.
Go to the 3D window of the virtual model rendering type,
select the semi-transparent surface or display the frame to preview and check the potential problems.
Insert a costume that matches the size of the virtual model or create a costume for the virtual model.
Select the virtual model, then go to the property editor.
Under the surface settings, you can select the software model simulation.
Please remember to select CPU simulation, then turn on the simulation.
In this example, we will adjust the software model strength to 6500 and then check the final result.
In addition, you can also apply software model simulation to a simple structure object.
In this example, we are using a very simple object.
You can find it in the picture library, virtual model, fill-in model, and find it.
You need to select the virtual model display type.
Now we add the material outside of this model.
Create a rectangular board, place the board on the model.
Open the simulation, let it hang on the model.
Now we use the line sewing tool to sew the two ends of this fabric together.
In this example, we reduce the particle strength to 10,
then harden the board to make the simulation more stable and the effect more obvious.
Select the model, then open the software model simulation in the property editor.
Also remember to switch to CPU simulation, then turn on the simulation.
After opening the simulation, we will see the model under pressure transformation.
If your virtual model has an insertion part or a hole, a wrong spring will pop out.
In this example, this model has an insertion part.
This model also has a hole and insertion problem.
According to the conventional operation steps, this model is referred to as a virtual model.
After loading, we create a template to affect this model.
If you try to activate the software simulation function and open the simulation,
you will see the error prompt and point out the current file.
If you click OK, you will turn off the spring and disable the software model simulation.
Therefore, we again recommend that you open the semi-transparent display or open the display frame to check whether there is a problem affecting the software simulation.
If you want to use software model simulation for this model, you need to solve the problem first, then import the file into Marvelous Designer again.
That's all for this video. See you in the next video.